Guide to the Victor Remer Historical Archives of the Children's Aid Society 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) MS 111
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI - Financial and Fund-Raising Records, 1853-1974; 1165
  - Subseries VI.4 - Volumes. Supplement, circa 1858-1963; 220779; 82 Linear feet
    - Cash Disbursements. 1934-1936, 220920 (Volume 564)
    - General Ledger #14. 1939-1941, 220941 (Volume 579)
    - General Ledger #15. 1942-1944, 220945 (Volume 580)
    - General Ledger #16. 1945-1947, 220948 (Volume 581)
    - General Ledger #17. 1948-1950, 220951 (Volume 582)
    - General Ledger #18. 1951-1953, 220954 (Volume 583)
    - General Ledger #19. 1954-1955, 220964 (Volume 584)
    - Special Appropriations (1938), 222609 (Volume 595)
    - Special Appropriations (1939), 222610 (Volume 596)
    - Special Appropriations (1940), 222611 (Volume 597)
    - Special Appropriations (1941), 222612 (Volume 598)
    - Special Appropriations (1942), 222613 (Volume 599)
    - Special Appropriations (1943), 222614 (Volume 600)
    - Special Appropriations (1944), 222615 (Volume 601)
    - Special Appropriations (1945), 222616 (Volume 602)
    - Special Appropriations (1946), 222618 (Volume 603)
    - Special Appropriations (1947), 222619 (Volume 604)
    - Special Appropriations (1948), 222630 (Volume 605)
    - Special Appropriations (1949), 222631 (Volume 606)
    - Special Appropriations (1950), 222632 (Volume 607)
    - Special Appropriations (1951), 222634 (Volume 608)
    - Special Appropriations (1952), 222830 (Volume 649)
    - Special Appropriations (1953), 222842 (Volume 650)
    - Special Appropriations (1954), 222843 (Volume 651)
    - Special Appropriations (1955), 222844 (Volume 652)
    - Special Appropriations (1956), 222845 (Volume 653)
    - Special Appropriations (1957), 222846 (Volume 654)
    - Special Appropriations (1958), 222847 (Volume 655)
    - Special Appropriations (1959), 222848 (Volume 656)
    - Special Appropriations (1960), 222849 (Volume 657)
    - Special Appropriations (1961), 222850 (Volume 658)
    - Cash Book. 1909 Feb-Sept, 222641 (Volume 609)
    - Cash Book. 1910 Sept-1911 March, 1910-1911; 222642 (Volume 610)
    - Cash Book. 1911 April-Sept, 222643 (Volume 611)
    - Cash Book. 1911 Oct-1912 Feb, 1911-1912; 222644 (Volume 612)
    - Cash Book. 1912 March-July, 222645 (Volume 613)
    - Cash Book. 1912 August-1913 March, 1912-1913; 222647 (Volume 614)
    - Cash Book. 1913 March-Sept, 222649 (Volume 615)
    - Cash Book. 1913 Oct-1914 March, 1913-1914; 222650 (Volume 616)
    - Cash Book. 1914 April-Sept, 222651 (Volume 617)
    - Cash Book. 1914 Oct-1915 Sept, 1914-1915; 222781 (Volume 618)
      Page 286 includes an adjustment for the period, dated March 1916.
    - Cash Book. 1915 Oct-1916 June, 1915-1916; 222782 (Volume 619)
    - Cash Book. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917; 222783 (Volume 620)
    - Cash Book. 1917 July-1918 June, 1917-1918; 222784 (Volume 621)
    - Cash Book. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920; 222789 (Volume 622)
    - Cash Book. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921; 222790 (Volume 623)
    - Cash Book. 1922 July-Oct, 222791 (Volume 624)
    - Voucher Register. 1951 Jan-June, 222798 (Volume 625)
    - Voucher Register. 1951 July-Dec, 222799 (Volume 626)
    - Voucher Register. 1952 Jan-June, 222800 (Volume 627)
    - Voucher Register. 1952 July-Dec, 222801 (Volume 628)
    - Voucher Register. 1953 Jan-June, 222802 (Volume 629)
    - Voucher Register. 1953 July-Dec, 222803 (Volume 630)
    - Voucher Register. 1954 Jan-June, 222804 (Volume 631)
    - Voucher Register. 1954 July-Dec, 222805 (Volume 632)
    - Voucher Register. 1955 Jan-June, 222806 (Volume 633)
    - Voucher Register. 1955 July-Dec, 222807 (Volume 634)
    - Voucher Register. 1956 Jan-June, 222808 (Volume 635)
    - Voucher Register. 1956 July-Dec, 222809 (Volume 636)
    - Voucher Register. 1957 Jan-June, 222812 (Volume 637)
    - Voucher Register. 1957 July-Dec, 222813 (Volume 638)
    - Voucher Register. 1958 Jan-June, 222814 (Volume 639)
    - Voucher Register. 1958 July-Dec, 222815 (Volume 640)
    - Voucher Register. 1959 Jan-June, 222816 (Volume 641)
    - Voucher Register. 1959 July-Dec, 222817 (Volume 642)
    - Voucher Register. 1960 Jan-June, 222819 (Volume 643)
    - Voucher Register. 1960 July-Dec, 222821 (Volume 644)
    - Voucher Register. 1961 Jan-June, 222822 (Volume 645)
    - Voucher Register. 1961 July-Dec, 222823 (Volume 646)
    - Voucher Register. 1962 Jan-June, 222824 (Volume 647)
    - Voucher Register. 1962 July-Dec, 222825 (Volume 648)
    - Prepaid Insurance, 1944-1949; 222851 (Volume 659)
    - Insurance Register, 1955-1959; 222852 (Volume 660)
    - Security Ledger (Investments), 1959-1961; 222853 (Volume 661)
      Includes record of securities held 1959-61 and associated income received during the period.
    - Custodian Account (Investments), 1959-1961; 222854 (Volume 662)
    - Board Summary (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1947-1949, 222885 (Volume 666)
    - Board Summaries (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1950-1952, 222887 (Volume 667)
    - Board Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1953-1955, 222888 (Volume 668)
    - Board Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1956-1958, 222889 (Volume 669)
    - Board & Clothing Book (Board, Clothing & Other Allowances). 1959-1961, 222890 (Volume 670)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1948-1951, 222893 (Volume 671)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1952-1955, 222891 (Volume 672)
    - Summary of Expenses. 1956-1959, 222894 (Volume 673)
    - Expenditure Register. 1914 Oct-1916 June, 1914-1916; 222860 (Volume 663)
    - Expenditure Register. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917; 222861 (Volume 664)
    - Expenditure Register. 1918 July-1919 June, 1918-1919; 222862 (Volume 665)
    - Expenditure Register. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920; 222865 (Volume 674)
    - Expenditure Register. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921; 222866 (Volume 675)
    - Expenditure Register. 1922 July-Sept, 222867 (Volume 676)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1951 May-August, 223674 (Volume 677)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 Jan-April, 223675 (Volume 678)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 May-August, 223676 (Volume 679)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1952 Sept-Dec, 223677 (Volume 680)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 Jan-April, 223678 (Volume 681)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 May-August, 223679 (Volume 682)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1953 Sept-Dec, 223680 (Volume 683)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 Jan-April, 223681 (Volume 684)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 May-August, 223682 (Volume 685)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1954 Sept-Dec, 223683 (Volume 686)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 Jan-April, 223684 (Volume 687)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 May-August, 223685 (Volume 688)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1955 Sept-Dec, 223686 (Volume 689)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 Jan-April, 223687 (Volume 690)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 May-August, 223688 (Volume 691)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1956 Sept-Dec, 223689 (Volume 692)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 Jan-April, 223690 (Volume 693)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 May-August, 223691 (Volume 694)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1957 Sept-Dec, 223692 (Volume 695)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 Jan-April, 223693 (Volume 696)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 May-August, 223694 (Volume 697)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1958 Sept-Dec, 223695 (Volume 698)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 Jan-April, 223696 (Volume 699)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 May-August, 223697 (Volume 700)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1959 Sept-Dec, 223698 (Volume 701)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 Jan-April, 223699 (Volume 702)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 May-August, 223700 (Volume 703)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1960 Sept-Dec, 223701 (Volume 704)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 Jan-April, 223702 (Volume 705)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 May-August, 223703 (Volume 706)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1961 Sept-Dec, 223704 (Volume 707)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 Jan-April, 223705 (Volume 708)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 May-August, 223706 (Volume 709)
    - Analysis of Expense. 1962 Sept-Dec, 223707 (Volume 710)
    - Income Register. 1914 October-1917 June, 1914-1917; 223708 (Volume 711)
    - Income Register. 1959-1961, 220933 (Volume 573)
    - Income Analysis. 1932-1935, 223709 (Volume 712)
    - Income Analysis. 1936-1938, 223710 (Volume 713)
    - Income Analysis. 1939-1942, 223711 (Volume 714)
    - Income Analysis. 1952-1955, 223712 (Volume 715)
    - Income Analysis. 1956-1960, 223713 (Volume 716)
    - Income Analysis. 1961-1963, 223714 (Volume 717)
    - Cash Receipts. 1950-1952, 223715 (Volume 718)
    - Donations. 1909 Oct-1910 Sept, 1909-1910; 223716 (Volume 719)
    - Donations. 1910 Oct-1911 Sept, 1910-1911; 223717 (Volume 720)
    - Donations. 1911 Oct-1912 Sept, 1911-1912; 223718 (Volume 721)
    - Donations. 1913 Oct-1914 Sept, 1913-1914; 223719 (Volume 722)
    - Donations. 1914 Oct-1915 Sept, 1914-1915; 223720 (Volume 723)
    - Donations. 1915 Oct-1916 June, 1915-1916; 223721 (Volume 724)
    - Donations. 1916 July-1917 June, 1916-1917; 223722 (Volume 725)
    - Donations. 1918 July-1919 June, 1918-1919; 223723 (Volume 726)
    - Donations. 1919 July-1920 June, 1919-1920; 223724 (Volume 727)
    - Donations. 1920 July-1921 June, 1920-1921; 223725 (Volume 728)
    - Donations. 1921 July-1922 June; 1924 December, 1921-1922, 1924; 223732 (Volume 729)
      In addition to the volume's principal entries for the 1921-22 period, the volume also includes the records for 18-31 December 1924, forwarded from page 251 of the volume for July-Dec 1924.
    - Donations. 1922 June-1923 June, 1922-1923; 223734 (Volume 730)
    - Donations. 1923 July-1924 May, 1923-1924; 223747 (Volume 731)
      Includes several loose sheets with summaries for years from 1917-1925.
    - Donations. 1924 Dec-1925 Dec; 1926 Dec, 1924-1926; 223788 (Volume 732)
      The volume principally includes entries for 1925, but also includes a few opening entries from late December of 1924 and some "spillover" entries from late December 1926.
    - Donations. 1925 Dec-1926 Dec, 1925-1926; 223789 (Volume 733)
    - Donations. 1927 Jan-Dec, 223790 (Volume 734)
    - Donations. 1929 Jan-Dec, 223791 (Volume 735)
    - Donations. 1930 Jan-Dec, 223792 (Volume 736)
    - Donations. 1931 Jan-1932 Jan, 1931-1932; 223793 (Volume 737)
    - Donations. 1932 Jan-Dec, 223794 (Volume 738)
    - Donations. 1934 Jan-Dec, 223795 (Volume 739)
    - Donations. 1935 Jan-Dec, 223796 (Volume 740)
    - Donations. 1939 Jan-Dec, 223797 (Volume 741)
    - Donations. 1940 Jan-Dec, 223798 (Volume 742)
    - Donations. 1941 Jan-Dec, 223799 (Volume 743)
    - Donations. 1936 Jan-Dec, 223800 (Volume 744)
    - Donations. 1937 Jan-Dec, 223801 (Volume 745)
    - Donations. 1938 Jan-Dec; 1939 Dec, 1938-1939; 223802 (Volume 746)
      The volume includes "spillover" entries for the final days of 1939 December.
    - Donations. 1943 Jan-June, 223803 (Volume 747)
    - Donations. 1943 July-Dec, 223804 (Volume 748)
    - Donations. 1944 Jan-July, 223805 (Volume 749)
    - Donations. 1944 July-Dec, 223806 (Volume 750)
    - Opera Benefit. 1937-1939, 226248 (Volume 751)
    - [Cash Journal]. 1902 October-1906 September, 1902-1906; 226249 (Volume 752)
    - Trial Balance. 1938-1942, 226250 (Volume 753)
    - Trial Balance. 1943-1947, 226251 (Volume 754)
    - [Bank Account Reconciliations]. 1951-1955, 226255 (Volume 755)
    - Donations, Special Campaigns. 1928 December-1931 March, 1928-1931; 226256 (Volume 756)
    - Journal #5 [Fund Investments], 1941-1948; 226260 (Volume 757)
    - [Payroll Summary?]. 1938-1942, 226263 (Volume 758)
    - Receipts & Donations / Cash Book. 1874 January-1880 December, 1874-1880; 226290 (Volume 759)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Continuation of Charles Loring Brace Account Book?;see volume 79 for 1867-73 entries. See volume 125 for 1880-1885 entries.
    - [Cash Book]. 1868 Dec-1872 Feb, 1868-1872; 226309 (Volume 760)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Appears to continue in volume 90.
    - [Cash Book]. 1870 March-1872 Feb, 1870-1872; 226310 (Volume 761)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Cash Book]. 1874 June-1876 March, 1874-1876; 226311 (Volume 762)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1876 April-1877 July, 1876-1877; 226312 (Volume 763)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1877 August-1878 July, 1877-1878; 226313 (Volume 764)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1880 July-1881 June, 1880-1881; 226314 (Volume 765)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1882 July-1883 July, 226315 (Volume 766)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1884 August-1885 July, 226316 (Volume 767)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1885 August-1886 July, 1885-1886; 226317 (Volume 768)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1886 August-1887 July, 226318 (Volume 769)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1887 August-1888 July, 226319 (Volume 770)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures].1888 August-1889 July, 226320 (Volume 771)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1890 September-1891 August, 226321 (Volume 772)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1891 September-1892 July, 226322 (Volume 773)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1892 August-1893 June, 226323 (Volume 774)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1893 July-1894 April, 226324 (Volume 775)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1894 May-1895 February, 226325 (Volume 776)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1895 March-October, 226326 (Volume 777)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1895 November-1896 October; 1897 October, 226327 (Volume 778)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. The pages run to 1896 October, but the last page shows as 1897 October 31, which is where next volume picks up. Not clear where 1986 Nov-1897 October is. Possibly the 1897 reference is an error.
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1897 November-1898 October, 226328 (Volume 779)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1898 November-1899 September, 226329 (Volume 780)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1900 October-1901 September, 226330 (Volume 781)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1902 September-1903 September, 226331 (Volume 782)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1904 October-1905 September, 226332 (Volume 783)
    - [Cash Book. Expenditures]. 1905 October-1906 September, 226333 (Volume 784)
    - [ Receipts and Donations]. 1902 October-1903 September, 226334 (Volume 785)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. I includes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [ Receipts and Donations]. 1904 October-1905 September (Volume 786)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Includes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [Receipts and Donations]. 1905 October-1906 September (Volume 787)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Iincludes a monthly summary inside back cover.
    - [Receipts and Donations]. 1906 October-1907 September (Volume 788)
    - [Donations]. 1908 October-1909 September (Volume 789)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register]. 1914 October-1915 September (Volume 790)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables]. 1915 October-1916 June (Volume 791)
      Includes Poor Law Officers Accounts. The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1917 July-1918 June (Volume 792)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1918 July-1919 June (Volume 793)
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1919 July 1920 June (Volume 794)
      Includes Poor Law Officers Accounts, including a summary of outstanding balances as of 1920 June). The covers and spine are badly deteriorated.
    - [Expenses Due and Paid Register; Income Receivables] 1920 July-1921 June (Volume 795)
    - [Expenditures Ledger] circa 1858 February-1868 December (Volume 796)
      The covers and spine are badly deteriorated. Volume 57 with expenses for 1853-57 appears to be the preceding volume.
    - Industrial Schools. Special Donation Accounts. 1903-1907 (Volume 797)
    - [Expense Allocation by Facility, Emigration, etc.] 1903 October-1905 September (Volume 798)
    - [Expense Allocation by Facility, Emigration, etc.] 1905 October-1907 December (Volume 799)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1885 November-1887 October (Volume 800)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1892 November-1893 October (Volume 801)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1896 November-1897 October (Volume 802)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1897 October-1898 October (Volume 803)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1898 November-1899 October (Volume 804)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1899 October-1900 September (Volume 805)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1900 September-1901 September (Volume 806)
    - [Cash Book. Receipts]. 1901 October-1902 September (Volume 807)
- Series VII - Legal Records, circa 1861-1925; 1166
  This series consists of 1 box of documents relating to miscellaneous legal matters, in folders arranged chronologically circa 1861-1925, and one volume (a mostly handwritten compilation of laws relating to gifts to charitable agencies 1848-1893; date of compilation unknown). The documents are mainly legal instruments (agreements, contracts, bonds, licenses), requests or petitions for legislation, as well as a few reports and letters regarding legal issues, and copies of legislation effecting the CAS. The volume is listed after the boxes in the container list.
  - Copy of a petition to the N.Y. State Legislature: CAS requesting a share in the "School Fund" for CAS schools, circa 1861; 2382 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1)
  - An Act providing for the county of NY to make up for the shortfall of the CAS for the year 1871, circa 1871; 2383 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 2)
  - Warrant in the case of two boys, Nicola Saraceno and Giuseppe Gallicano, giving custody of them to CAS, 1873 August 1; 2384 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 3)
  - NY State Senate bill: "An Act for the Protection of Factory Children and Other Persons", 1874 January 22; 2385 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 4)
  - Sheperds Fold vs. the Mayor: Lawsuit to repeal tax (2 documents), 1882 and undated; 2386 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 5)
  - Arguments re: legality of appropriations from the Common School Fund to the industrial schools of the CAS, 1883 May 29; 2387 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 6)
  - State of NY, State Board of Charities, Laws of 1884, Chapter 438, 2388 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 7)
  - "An Act to Regulate the Employment of Women and Children in Manufacturing Establishments" - page from Laws of NY, 1886; 2389 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 8)
  - Legal opinion of Judge H.C. Van Vorst in justification of CAS charter amendment, transcribed excerpt from minutes, 1888 December 19; 2390 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 9)
  - Publishing contract between Charles Loring Brace and A.C. Armstrong & Son to publish "The Unknown God; or Inspiration Among Pre-Christian Races", 1890 April 30; 2391 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 10)
  - Legal opinion that CAS children are not "inmates" among other matters, 1895 March 13; 2392 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 11)
  - Joint letter by CAS and 6 other charities in opposition to bill giving too much power to State Board of Charities, and a copy of the bill, and a substitute bill proposed by charities, 1898 February 25; 2393 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 12)
  - Legal document: Bond: John J. McDonald to pay Julia G. Inness, 1900 January 18; 2394 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 13)
  - Legal Document: General Release, 1902 October 2 and 6; 2395 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 14)
  - Report on history of laws and policies relating to abandoned children, and a draft of same, by unknown CAS author for unknown audience, undated, post-1903; 2396 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 15)
  - "Protestant Children Under Catholic Care": a report by the CAS Probation Commission regarding probation legislation, undated, circa 1906; 2397 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 16)
  - Copies of agreements and receipts with the National Surety Co. guaranteeing againg diseased children becoming a public charge in Iowa and Nebraska, 1907, 1923, 1926; 2398 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 17)
  - Legal Document: General Release, 1908 September 30; 2399 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 18)
  - Legal document: 2 General Releases, 1918; 2400 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 19)
  - Legal document re: estate of Sarah H. Crosby and her real estate, 1914 March 31; 2401 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 20)
  - Agreements for the Endowment of Beds, 1919 December; 2402 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 21)
  - CAS license to run child caring and placing agency in Lansing Michigan, undated, circa 1925; 2403 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 22)
  - Acts of the Legislature in Favor of the Children's Aid Society, 1848-1893; 2404 (Volume 262)
- Series VIII - Real Estate Records, circa 1869-1964; 1167
  Series VIII consists of 1 box and 1 oversize box of documents relating to CAS real estate, arranged chronologically 1873-1964, and 3 volumes [circa 1869]-1961. The documents in the boxes include deeds, leases, contracts, a small amount of correspondence, and architectural drawings.
  The first box (box 38) consists of folders arranged chronologically 1873-1964, including 3 folders related to work for the CAS by the architectural firm of Calvert Vaux & George Radford interfiled with the other real estate material. Some of the folders in this box include groups of leases, contracts or other documents related to a single property over a span of years, and these are arranged chronologically according to the first document in the folder.
  The second box (OS1) is an oversize box of 4 architectural drawings on drafting linen (3 exteriors, 1 cutaway) of the Rhinelander School by the firm of Vaux & Radford circa 1890. The drawings, numbered 7, 8, 9 and 12, appear to be part of a series of drawings, but the location of the remaining drawings is unknown.
  Series VIII also includes three volumes regarding real estate owned by the CAS. The volumes appear in the container list at the end of the series, after the boxes.
  See also Edwin Merrill Correspondence, Series IV.3.D, for more material relating to real estate. See also Series IX - Facilities - for material about specific properties, including oversize property surveys, arranged according to facility.
  - Deed granting land in Virginia to CAS, 1873 March 28; 2405 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1)
  - Notice of property on Rivington Street sold for the collection of 1868 taxes, 1874 March 18; 2406 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 2)
  - Summons for non-payment of rent on 68th Street, 1874 October 12; 2407 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3)
  - Contract re: transfer of 43rd Street property to CAS, 1881 January 26; 2408 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 4)
  - Lease for a room in church building on East 19th Street, 1882 May 1; 2409 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 5)
  - Lease for a ferry landing at Bath Beach, Coney Island, 1882 May 18; 2410 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 6)
  - Agreement to allow Brooklyn to build a well on CAS property at Bath Beach Coney Island, and agreement for use of well, 1882 July 10 and 1887 September 23; 2411 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and leases re: 208 Bleecker Street property, 1882, 1887-1891; 2412 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 8)
  - Leases for 24 Sullivan Street property, 1882, 1887, 1908; 2413 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 9)
  - Leases of rooms for 53rd Street School, 1883, 1888; 2414 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 10)
  - Contracts between CAS and Vaux & Radford, 1883-1889; 2415 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence between CAS and Vaux & Radford and subcontractors, 1885-1889 and undated; 2416 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 12)
  - Leases for 68th Street property, 1885 April, 1888 July; 2417 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 13)
  - Contracts re: purchase and sale of property in Gravesend (Brooklyn), 1885 May, 1920 February; 2418 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 14)
  - Agreement to build two Health Home cottages, 1886 March 8; 2419 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 15)
  - Lease for 93 Crosby Street property, 1886 March 18; 2420 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 16)